OpenSubtitles recommends using Nord VPN
Apףyanos y conviיrtete en miembro VIP Para eliminar todos los anuncios www.OpenSubtitles.org
Fuck. What the fuck?
Carajo. ¿ Quי diablos?
What the...?
¿ Quי?
What the fuck!
¡Quי diablos!
Fuck.
Carajo.
Hello?
¿Hola?
Hello, Seth.
Hola, Seth.
I wanna play a game.
Quiero jugar.
Right now, you're feeling helpless.
Ahora mismo, te sientes indefenso.
- This is the same helplessness... - Help!
- Es el mismo sentimiento... - ¡Ayuda!
... you've bestowed onto others.
... que has otorgado a otros.
But now it's onto you.
Pero ahora te toca a ti.
Some call this karma. I call it justice.
Algunos lo llaman karma. Yo lo llamo justicia.
Now, you served five years...
Ahora, pagaste cinco aסos...
... of what should have been a life sentence for murder.
... de lo que debiף haber sido una cadena perpetua por asesinato.
A technicality gave you freedom...
Un tecnicismo te dio libertad...
... but it inhibited you from understanding...
... pero no te permitiף entender el impacto de arrebatar una vida.
Today, I offer you true freedom.
Hoy, yo te ofrezco una verdadera libertad.
In 30 seconds, the pendulum will drop far enough to touch your body.
En 30 segundos, el pיndulo caerב tan cerca de ti que tocarב tu cuerpo.
Within sixty seconds it will cut you in half.
En sesenta segundos te cortarב a la mitad.
To avoid the pendulum...
Para evitar el pיndulo...
... all you have to do is destroy the things that have killed.
... lo תnico que debes hacer es destruir lo que ha matado.
Your hands.
Tus manos.
You must insert your hands and push the buttons...
Debes insertar tus manos y presionar los botones para iniciar los dispositivos.
Your bones will be crushed to dust.
Tus huesos serבn aplastados hasta hacerlos polvo.
Will you destroy the things that have taken life in order to save one, Seth?
¿ Destruirבs las cosas que han...
Make your choice.
Tת eliges.
No.
No.
It was an accident!
¡Fue un accidente!
Please.
Por favor.
Okay. Fuck you.
Estב bien. Jףdete.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
Bien. Bien. Bien.
I did what I was supposed to do.
Ya sabםas lo que iba a hacer.
Let me see your hands. Let me see your fucking hands.
Muestra tus manos. Dיjame ver tus manos.
Where is my daughter? You...
¿Dףnde estב mi hija? Tת...
Jesus.
Jesתs.
Hello, Agent Strahm.
Hola, agente Strahm.
If you're hearing this...
Si escuchas esto...
... then you've finally found what you've been looking for.
... es que finalmente encontraste lo que has estado buscando.
But is the discovery of my body enough?
¿ Pero es suficiente el descubrimiento de mi cuerpo?
Or will your insatiable hunger to uncover the truth...
¿ O tu hambre insaciable por descubrir la verdad te empujף al abismo?
Heed my warning: Do not proceed.
Considera mi advertencia: No procedas.
For this room can either be your sanctuary or it can be your grave.
Porque este cuarto puede ser tu santuario o tu tumba.
The choice is yours.
Tת eliges.
Fuck you.
Jףdete.
Hey!
¡Oigan!
Help!
¡Ayuda!
Go! Go!
¡Vamos! ¡Vamos!
You're okay.
Estבs bien.
- Where's my dad? - He's gonna be okay.
- ¿ Y mi padre? - ֹI estarב bien.
Where's my mom?
¿Dףnde estב mi mamב?
- Hoffman. - I got it. I got it.
- Hoffman. - Lo tengo. Lo tengo.
You okay to walk?
¿Te pegaste con una pared?
What the hell, man? What happened? Where's Rigg?
¿ Quי demonios, hombre? ¿ Quי pasף? ¿ Y Rigg?
Tried to help. He didn't make it.
Tratף de ayudar. No sobreviviף.
Nobody made it.
Nadie sobreviviף.
We got a live one.
Tenemos uno vivo.
Hello?
¿Hola?
Right away.
En este instante.
Ms. Tuck.
Seסora Tuck.
Have a seat.
Tome asiento.
It's nice to meet you, Mr. Feldman.
Es un placer conocerlo, seסor Feldman.
Why am I here?
¿Por quי estoy aquם?
I represent your ex-husband, John.
Represento a su ex esposo, John.
In the event of his death, I was instructed to contact you.
En caso de su muerte, yo debםa contactarla.
You can understand my surprise when I found out who he really was.
Podrב entender mi sorpresa cuando me enterי de quiיn era realmente.
John left something for you.
John dejף algo para usted.
If you're watching this, Jill, I'm long gone from this world.
Si estבs viendo esto, Jill, es que ya me fui de este mundo.
You are my heart, you always have been. You always will be.
Eres mi corazףn, siempre lo has sido. Siempre lo serבs.
I'm not going to try to explain my actions of late.
No tratarי de explicar mis acciones.
Suffice it to say that I find it difficult to forgive myself...
Basta decir que me cuesta mucho perdonarme...
... for what happened at the clinic.
... por lo sucedido en la clםnica.
I permitted, indeed, encouraged your decisions regarding the people there.
Yo permitם, de hecho, alentי tus decisiones acerca de la gente de ahם.
I saw danger and l... I should have acted sooner.
Vi peligro y... Debם haber actuado antes.
I'm leaving you a box today, and its contents are of grave importance.
Te dejo una caja, y su contenido es de suma importancia.
Even though you and I don't always see eye to eye on everything...
Aunque tת y yo no siempre miramos cuidadosamente todo...
... I deeply believe in you and I believe that you will know...
... creo profundamente en ti y creo que sabrבs...
... what to do with these materials.
... quי hacer con esos materiales.
I wanna thank you all for coming here today.
Quiero agradecerles a todos por venir hoy.
And I'd like to be the first to say...
Y me gustarםa ser el primero en decir...
...that the Jigsaw murders are over.
...que los asesinatos de Jigsaw se acabaron.
The officers who gave their lives are being honored here today.
Los oficiales que dieron sus vidas son homenajeados el dםa de hoy.
But today I'd like to offer a special honor...
Pero hoy me gustarםa reconocer especialmente...
...to the detective who's been on this case right from the beginning...
...al detective que ha estado en este caso desde el principio...
...who proved through hard work and dedication...
...que probף a travיs del trabajo duro y la dedicaciףn...
...that the people who died did not die in vain.
...que la gente que muriף, no muriף en vano.
Today we honor the newly promoted Detective Lieutenant...
Hoy homenajeamos a quien acaba de ser ascendido a detective teniente...
...Mark Hoffman.
...Mark Hoffman.
Congratulations.
Felicidades.
Thank you so much.
Muchas gracias.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Gracias. Muchas gracias.
Throughout this ordeal, if we've learned anything it's that...
A travיs de esta terrible experiencia, si aprendimos algo es que...
...human life is sacred.
...la vida humana es sagrada.
And we've learned that every day...
Y hemos aprendido que cada dםa...
...life should be cherished.
...la vida debe ser valorada.
Justice...
La justicia...
...is the backbone to every peaceful society.
...es el eje de una sociedad pacםfica.
And I believe that true justice has been served.
Y creo que la verdadera justicia ha sido impartida.
Detective Hoffman, you're wanted at the hospital.
Detective Hoffman, lo solicitan en el hospital.
It's about Agent Perez.
Es acerca de la agente Perez.
Thank you.
Gracias.
Hello, Agent Perez, and welcome to the world that you have long studied.
Hola, agente Perez, y bienvenida al mundo que ha estado estudiando.
Heed my warning, Agent Perez.
Considere mi advertencia, agente Perez.
Your next move is critical.
Su siguiente movimiento es crםtico.
- Open the door. - What is that?
- Abra la puerta. - ¿ Quי es eso?
I got you.
Te tengo.
I'm truly sorry about Agent Perez.
De verdad siento lo de la agente Perez.
She said your name, you know.
Dijo tu nombre.
The last thing she said was "Detective Hoffman."
Lo תltimo que dijo fue "Detective Hoffman".
Why'd she say that? Why'd she say your name?
¿Por quי dijo eso? ¿Por quי dirםa tu nombre?
- I don't know. - No?
- No lo sי. - ¿No?
How'd you walk out of that building?
¿ Cףmo saliste de ese edificio?
How did you?
¿ Cףmo lo hiciste tת?
On a gurney with a fucking hole in my throat.
En una camilla con un agujero en mi garganta.
Look at you.
Mםrate.
Couple of scratches and a story about how your arm straps broke.
Un par de rasguסos y una historia de cףmo tu arnיs se rompiף.
Jigsaw doesn't make mistakes.
Jigsaw no comete errores.
Is this you theorizing again? Because Jigsaw's dead.
¿Estבs teorizando nuevamente? Porque Jigsaw estב muerto.
I'm not talking about him...
No hablo de יl, hablo de ti y de tu torcido departamento.
My department's gone. They're all dead. There's no one left.
Ya no tengo departamento. Todos estבn muertos. No queda nadie.
Besides you.
Aparte de ti.
Been chasing Jigsaw from the beginning...
Busquי a Jigsaw desde el principio...
...and I got him.
...y lo atrapי.
So unless you've got something else to say...
Asם que a menos que quieras decir algo mבs...
...back the fuck off.
...apבrtate.
Read the papers. I saved that little girl.
Lee los periףdicos. Yo salvי a esa niסa.
Sorry about Agent Perez.
Siento lo de la agente Perez.
Shouldn't you be resting?
¿No deberםas descansar?
I'm fine, Erickson.
Estoy bien, Erickson.
No, you're not, Peter. That's why I put you on medical leave.
No, no lo estבs, Peter. Por eso te puse en licencia mיdica.
I was supposed to die in that trap.
Debם haber muerto en esa trampa.
You never should have been there without backup.
Nunca debiste haber ido sin refuerzos.
I wanna talk to Jill Tuck one last time.
Quiero hablar con Jill Tuck una vez mבs.
You're no longer handling the case, Peter.
Tת ya no llevas el caso, Peter.
What?
¿ Quי?
Read it.
Lיelo.
Over a dozen dead bodies were recovered at the scene...
Casi una docena de cadבveres estaban ahם, dos eran policםas.
Jigsaw's dead, how many lives did I inevitably save?
Jigsaw estב muerto, ¿ cuבntas vidas salvי?
By endangering yourself and others.
Poniיndolos a ustedes y a otros en peligro.
You're off the case.
Estבs fuera del caso.
On whose orders?
¿ Segתn ordenes de quiיn?
Mine.
Mםas.
I'm sorry, Peter. It's over.
Lo siento, Peter. Se acabף.
Oh, my God.
Por Dios.
- What is this? - Hey, don't move.
- ¿ Quי es esto? - Oye, no te muevas.
What did you do to me?
¿ Quי me hiciste?
I didn't do anything.
Yo no hice nada.
- It's Jigsaw. - What?
- Es Jigsaw. - ¿ Quי?
I knew this was gonna happen to me. This is what he does.
Sabםa que esto me pasarםa a mם. Esto es lo que hace.
No, it's not Jigsaw.
No, no es Jigsaw.
He's dead.
Estב muerto.
Haven't you watched TV lately?
¿No has visto la televisiףn תltimamente?
Yeah, well, whoever it is...
Sם, bueno, quien sea...
...they're watching us.
...nos estבn viendo.
To make sure we follow the rules.
Para asegurarse que seguimos las reglas.
- Which are what? - I wouldn't do that if I were you.
- ¿ Cuבles son? - Yo no harםa eso.
Unless you want your head to pop off like a dandelion.
A menos que quieras que la cabeza se te caiga.
- How do you know that? - Because I have eyes.
- ¿ Cףmo sabes eso? - Porque tengo ojos.
One pull-pin starts the timer for all of us.
Un botףn activa el reloj para todos.
You won't wanna do that unless you know how it works, now, would you?
¿No harםas eso a menos que supieras cףmo funciona, no?
You're starting to freak me out, dude.
Me estבs asustando, amigo.
Hello, and welcome.
Hola, y bienvenidos.
From birth, you've all been given the advantages of few others.
Desde el inicio, les han dado mבs ventajas que a los demבs.
Yet through poor moral decisions...
Pero a travיs de pobres decisiones morales...
... you've used these advantages to selfishly further...
... han usado esas ventajas para satisfacerse egoםstamente...
... only yourselves at the expense of others.
... solo ustedes a expensas de los otros.
Well, today this singular way of thinking will be put to the test.
Bueno, hoy esta singular manera de pensar serב puesta a prueba.
Today, five will become one, with a common goal of survival.
Hoy, los cinco serבn uno, con la meta comתn de sobrevivir.
You are all connected.
Todos estבn conectados.
A cable runs through your collar devices.
Un cable pasa por sus dispositivos del cuello.
It can be pulled so tight...
Se puede jalar tan fuerte...
... that you will be decapitated on the mounted razors.
... que serםan decapitados por las navajas.
The only way to remove the collar is with the keys from the glass boxes...
La תnica manera de quitarse el collar...
... on the pedestals before you.
... en los pedestales de enfrente.
However, if one of you moves to retrieve a key...
Sin embargo, si uno de ustedes se mueve para tomar una llave...
... the 60-second timer will begin for you all.
... el reloj de 60 segundos se activarב para todos.
In choosing how to react to this situation...
Al elegir cףmo reaccionar ante la situaciףn...
... your lifelong instincts will tell you to do one thing...
... sus instintos les dirבn que hagan una cosa...
... but I implore you to do the opposite.
... pero les imploro que hagan lo opuesto.
Let the games begin.
Que comiencen los juegos.
Somebody has to die.
Alguien tiene que morir.
No, no, no, it says, "Don't listen to your instincts."
No, no, no, dijo, "No escuchen a sus instintos".
- That means don't go for the keys. - You fucking nuts?
- Eso significa no ir por las llaves. - ¿Estבs loca?
How are we supposed to live if we don't?
¿ Cףmo sobreviviremos si no lo hacemos?
- It's testing our endurance. - We gotta move, babe.
- Prueba nuestra resistencia. - Tenemos que actuar.
That timer's connected to those jars.
El reloj estב conectado a esos botes.
It didn't say anything about those jars.
No dijo nada de esos botes.
- They could be nothing. - They're nail bombs.
- Podrםan no ser nada. - Son bombas de clavos.
Homemade, probably C-4.
Hechas en casa, probablemente C-4.
How the fuck do you know that?
¿ Cףmo diablos sabes eso?
She's a fire inspector. She's seen all kinds of demented shit.
Es una inspectora de fuego. Ha visto muchas cosas dementes.
How do you know me?
¿ Cףmo me conoces?
Hey, man, she's asking you a question. How do you know her?
Oye, te estב preguntando algo. ¿ Cףmo es que la conoces?
How do you know her? Answer me!
¿ Cףmo la conoces? ¡Responde!
Look, let's just keep our cool.
Miren, mantengבmonos tranquilos.
- Okay, we can figure this out. - We're all here for a reason.
- Bien, podemos salir de esto. - Estamos aquם por algo.
Okay, and we're all connected, as the message said.
Bien, y todos estamos conectados como dice el mensaje.
We just need to...
Solo necesitamos...
- What did you do? - You go first.
- ¿ Quי hiciste? - Vas primero.
It said that we were all born with advantages.
Dijo que todos nacimos con ventajas.
Right? That means we're all from money.
¿No? Significa que todos tenemos dinero.
- I'm not. - And neither am I.
- Yo no. - Tampoco yo.
Hey, nice fucking try, Nancy Drew.
Buen intento, Nancy Drew.
Well, then, what does it mean?
Bueno, entonces, ¿ quי significa?
We did something wrong with an advantage from birth.
Hicimos algo mal con una ventaja que tenemos.
- That doesn't have to mean money. - What are you not telling us?
- Y no tiene que ser el dinero. - ¿ Quי no nos estבs diciendo?
You know about her, what do you know about the rest of us?
Sabes de ella, ¿ quי sabes de los demבs?
Would you fucking talk to me?
¿Me quieres decir algo, carajo?
- Relax. - I am fucking relaxed.
- Relבjate. - Estoy relajado.
It's a game, tweaker.
Es un juego, drogadicto.
Get it? The less you know about me, the better.
¿Entiendes? Mientras menos sepas de mם, mejor.
The reason why you fucked up your charmed existence...
La razףn por la cual arruinaste tu existencia...
...is pretty obvious to everyone, isn't it?
...es muy obvia para todos, ¿no?
Fuck you. Fuck you.
Jףdete. Jףdete.
Been playing with matches again, have we?
¿Has estado probando tu suerte, no?
Fuck all of you and your fucking plan.
Al diablo con ustedes y con su plan.
Unless you wanna be shredded when those bombs go off...
A menos que quieran ser destruidos por las bombas...
...I suggest we move on.
...sugiero que hagamos algo.
What are you doing?
¿ Quי haces?
Being smart.
Ser inteligente.
Special Agent Strahm's office.
Oficina del agente especial Strahm.
This is Detective Hoffman. Is Agent Strahm available?
Habla el detective Hoffman. ¿ Se encuentra el agente Strahm?
He's not, but I can connect you to Special Agent Erickson.
No, pero puede hablar con el agente especial Erickson.
He's handling all inquiries.
ֹI estב contestando todo.
Please.
Por favor.
You've reached the voice mail box of Agent Erickson.
Este es el buzףn de mensajes del agente Erickson.
Please leave a message.
Por favor, deje un mensaje.
Yeah, this is Detective Hoffman.
Sם, soy el detective Hoffman.
I needed to discuss something with Agent Strahm...
Necesito hablar algo con el agente Strahm...
...but I can't seem to track him down.
...pero no puedo encontrarlo.
Could you give me a call? It would be greatly appreciated.
¿Me podrםa llamar? De verdad se lo agradecerםa.
There you are.
Aquם estבs.
Sister.
Hermana.
Peter.
Peter.
- Cowan, take this to analysis. - Right away, sir.
- Cowan, lleva esto a anבlisis. - Ahora mismo, seסor.
What are you doing here?
¿ Quי haces aquם?
Just grabbing some stuff from the office. I'm taking your advice.
Tomaba algunas cosas de mi oficina. Tomarי su consejo.
- Taking some time off, huh? - Yeah, well, I have to heal up, you know.
- ¿Te tomarבs un tiempo? - Sם, bueno, tengo que curarme.
You know, I'll keep in touch. I'll see you around.
Me mantendrי en contacto. Nos vemos pronto.
Hoffman.
Hoffman.
We got another body. Looks like another Jigsaw victim.
Tenemos otro cadבver. Parece otra vםctima de Jigsaw.
- You up for this? - Yeah.
- ¿Listo para esto? - Sם.
Typical bio. Murder convict.
Biografםa tםpica. Condenado por asesinato.
Served five years, just released last month.
Encarcelado cinco aסos, saliף el mes pasado.
I know him.
Lo conozco.
His name's Seth Baxter.
Su nombre es Seth Baxter.
My sister's ex-boyfriend.
El ex novio de mi hermana.
This is the guy that murdered your sister?
¿ֹI es el chico que matף a tu hermana?
He was sentenced to 25 years. Got it reduced to five on a technicality.
Fue sentenciado a 25 aסos. Fueron cinco por un tecnicismo.
Well, then I'd say justice was served.
Bueno, yo dirםa que se impartiף la justicia.
You killed him. Made it look like a Jigsaw trap.
Tת lo mataste. Hiciste que pareciera obra de Jigsaw.
I got you.
Te tengo.
Not yet.
- Todavםa no. - No cierres la puerta. Activarב el reloj.
- Do you know that for sure? - Educated guess.
- ¿Lo sabes de cierto? - Es una adivinanza educada.
What we need to do is figure out who everyone is.
Lo que tenemos que hacer es saber quiיnes somos.
Okay, well, we know that the dead woman worked for the fire department.
Bueno, sabemos que la muerta...
Not anymore. She got canned a month ago.
Ya no. La dejaron ir hace un mes.
How the fuck do you...? How the fuck do you know that?
¿ Cףmo diablos? ¿ Cףmo diablos haces eso?
You're responsible for this? She had her fucking head cut off!
¿Tת eres responsable de esto? ¡Le cortaron la cabeza!
I'm closing the door.
¡Cerrarי la puerta!
Please.
Por favor.
What's your story?
¿ Cuבl es tu historia?
I work for the Department of City Planning.
Trabajo para el Departamento de Planeaciףn.
- Married? Kids? - No, and no. Your turn.
- ¿ Casada? ¿ Con hijos? - No, y no.
- My dad is Richard Gibbs. - The owner of the Cougars?
- Mi padre es Richard Gibbs. - ¿El dueסo de los Cougars?
He's been trying to build a new stadium for years. Little did he know...
Ha tratado de construir un estadio nuevo durante aסos. No sabםa...
...all he had to do is wait for his daughter to get a job in City Planning.
...que tan solo debםa esperar que su hija recibiera un trabajo en Planeaciףn.
And you. What about you?
Y tת. ¿ Quי hay de ti?
What sort of shady shit have you been up to?
¿A quי diablos te dedicas?
I'm a senior V.P. for a real estate development company.
Soy subdirectora de una compaסםa de desarrollo inmobiliario.
So you're boring too.
Asם que tambiיn eres aburrida.
The Marshvard Group. Yeah, you can't get a permit in this town...
El Grupo Marshvard. Sם, no puedes tener un permiso aquם...
...without going through the Department of City Planning.
...sin pasar por el Departamento de Planeaciףn.
- Right? - No, you can't.
- ¿ Cierto? - No, no puedes.
What about you?
¿ Y tת?
No wife.
Sin esposa.
- No kids that I know of. No job. - Trust-fund baby. Anyone surprised?
- Sin niסos que conozca. Sin trabajo. - Chico heredero. ¿Alguna sorpresa?
I'm so fucking sick of your self-righteousness.
Estoy harto de tus pretensiones.
It's your turn.
Es tu turno.
I'm an investigative journalist for The Herald.
Soy un periodista investigador para The Herald.
Herald? That's your accomplishment? You work for a gossip rag?
¿ Herald? ¿Es tu logro? ¿Trabajas en una columna de chismes?
Bite your fucking tongue.
Retira tus palabras.
What the hell are in those jars?
¿ Quי diablos hay en esos botes?
Let's do this fucking thing before the bombs go off.
Hagamos esto antes de que exploten las bombas.
Fuck!
¡Carajo!
Hello, and welcome to the next lesson.
Hola, y bienvenidos a la siguiente lecciףn.
These walls hold four chambers.
Estas paredes tienen cuatro cבmaras.
These chambers are for safety.
Estas cבmaras son de seguridad.
However, to access them, a key is needed.
Sin embargo, para acceder, se necesita una llave.
But only three of the keys will fit the locks.
Pero solo tres de las llaves funcionarבn.
These keys are in the glass jars hanging from the ceiling.
Dichas llaves estבn en los botes de vidrio en el techo.
Move quickly, though, because when the clock ticks down...
Muיvanse rבpido, porque cuando el reloj lo indique...
... the explosives in the corners of the room will detonate.
... los explosivos en las esquinas del cuarto explotarבn.
With only three points of safety, which of you will be the odd man out?
Con solo tres puntos de seguridad, ¿ quiיn de ustedes quedarב fuera?
Make your choice.
Ustedes eligen.
Fuck.
Carajo.
Fuck, it's blank. I need a shape.
Carajo, no tiene forma. Necesito una forma.
Get your hands off that, you're not going anywhere.
No lo intentes, no irבs a ningתn lado.
- Stop it! - Get a clue, you fucking bitch.
- ¡Detente! - No tienes idea, perra.
It's survival of the fittest.
Es la ley del mבs fuerte.
Blank.
Sin forma.
Shit.
Mierda.
I got it. Got it.
Lo tengo. Lo tengo.
Yes.
Sם.
Better luck next time, rich boy.
Suerte para la prףxima, niסo rico.
Survival of the fittest, my ass!
¡La ley del mבs fuerte, carajo!
Wait.
Espera.
Everything all right with Detective Kerr in the Seth Baxter case?
¿Todo bien con el detective Kerr en el caso Seth Baxter?
- Yeah. - Good.
- Sם. - Bien.
Fisk. You keep me posted.
Fisk. Tת mantenme informado.
- Will do. - Good.
- Lo harי. - Bien.
After Seth, you were involved in every investigation.
Despuיs de Seth, tת estuviste involucrado en cada investigaciףn.
When did you first meet Jigsaw?
¿ Cuבndo conociste a Jigsaw?
Stop it, stop it!
¡Detente, detente!
Don't!
¡No!
Heel! Heel, I said!
¡Tranquilo! ¡Tranquilo, dije!
Don't provoke him. Asshole!
¡No lo provoques estתpido!
Jesus Christ. Come on, Peewee. Come on.
Dios mםo. Vamos, Peewee. Vamos.
- Come on, Peewee. - Peewee.
- Vamos, Peewee. - Peewee.
Shit.
Mierda.
Do you mind?
Con permiso.
- Going up? - Yes, thank you.
- ¿ Va para arriba? - Sם, gracias.
What floor are you going to?
¿A quי piso va?
I think we're both going to the same place.
Creo que los dos vamos al mismo lugar.
You know why you're here, don't you?
¿ Sabes por quי estבs aquם, no?
They say imitation is the sincerest form of flattery.
Dicen que la imitaciףn es la forma mבs sincera de adular.
But I find it somewhat distasteful...
Pero se me hizo algo desagradable...
...to be given credit for work that's not mine.
...tomar el crיdito por trabajo que no es mםo.
Especially inferior work.
Especialmente trabajo mediocre.
Like you, I know what it's like to lose family.
Igual que tת, sי quי se siente perder una familia.
I know what it's like not to be able to protect loved ones.
Sי lo que se siente no poder proteger a tus seres queridos.
It's a powerless feeling.
Es un sentimiento de impotencia.
I wouldn't do that.
Yo no harםa eso.
Hair trigger.
Gatillo de pelo.
What do you see?
¿ Quי es lo que ves?
Vengeance can change a person. Make you into something...
La venganza puede cambiar a alguien. Convertirte en algo...
...you never thought you were capable of being.
...que nunca pensaste que serםas capaz de ser.
But unlike you, I've never killed anyone.
Pero a diferencia de ti, yo nunca matי a nadie.
- I give people a chance. - You call this a chance?
- Yo le di una oportunidad a la gente. - ¿Llamas a esto una oportunidad?
We'll see.
Ya lo veremos.
- Our game's just begun. - Our game? You don't even know me.
- El juego acaba de empezar. - ¿El juego? Tת no me conoces.
I know you. I've followed you as you've pursued me.
Te conozco. Te he seguido tanto como tת a mם.
I know you. I know about your sister.
Sי de ti. Sי de tu hermana.
I know how you cared for her.
Sי cuבnto la querםas.
I know she was your only family.
Sי que era tu תnica familia.
Leave me alone.
Dיjame en paz.
No!
¡No!
You sit in bars until closing. You drink so you can sleep.
Te quedas en bares hasta que cierran. Bebes para poder dormir.
You stagger to your car...
Te vas a tu auto...
...and then you start it all over again the next day.
...y comienzas la misma rutina al otro dםa.
Then I discovered what you do for recreation.
Entonces descubrם quי haces para entretenerte.
You can dispense justice...
Puedes conceder justicia...
...and give people a chance to value their lives in the same moment.
...y darle a la gente una oportunidad de valorar sus vidas en el mismo momento.
And by the way...
Y por cierto...
...the blade on your pendulum was inferior.
...la navaja en tu pיndulo fue inferior.
If you want a true edge...
Si quieres un verdadero filo...
...you have to used tempered steel.
...debes usar acero reforzado.
Tempering's better for the long haul.
El reforzado es mejor a largo plazo.
You in this for the long haul, detective?
¿Estבs en esto a largo plazo, detective?
I've been a cop for 20 years. Is that long enough for you?
He sido un policםa durante 20 aסos. ¿Es suficiente para ti?
Then you and I both know the statistics for repeat offenders in this city.
Entonces tת y yo sabemos las estadםsticas...
67.5 percent of criminals are back in prison within three years.
67,5 por ciento de los criminales...
What do you want from me?
¿ Quי quieres de mם?
So you might look at what you did to Seth as a kind of public service.
Puede que tת veas lo que le hiciste a Seth como un servicio pתblico.
She was my only family. He didn't deserve a chance.
Ella era mi תnica familia. No merecםa una oportunidad.
- He was an animal. - Everybody deserves a chance!
- ֹI era un animal. - ¡Todos merecen otra oportunidad!
You didn't see the blood!
¡Tת no viste la sangre!
You didn't see what he fucking did to her!
¡Tת no viste lo que le hizo!
Killing is distasteful...
Matar es de muy mal gusto...
...to me.
...para mם.
There is a better, more efficient way.
Hay una mejor y mבs eficiente manera.
What do you see...? Look!
¿ Quי es lo que ves? ¡Mira!
- What do you see? - Tell me what you want.
- ¿ Quי es lo que ves? - Dime quי es lo que quieres.
I wanna know if you have what it takes to survive.
Quiero saber si tienes lo que se necesita para sobrevivir.
Fuck you.
Jףdete.
You see, it's a different method that I'm talking about.
Verבs, estoy hablando de un mיtodo diferente.
If a subject survives my method...
Si un sujeto sobrevive mi mיtodo...
...he or she is instantly rehabilitated.
...יl o ella estב instantבneamente rehabilitado.
Now, you want a chance?
Ahora, ¿ quieres una oportunidad?
You want a chance?
¿ Quieres una oportunidad?
I'll give you a chance.
Te darי una oportunidad.
I'm the man you call Jigsaw.
Yo soy el hombre que llamas Jigsaw.
It's your duty to bring me in...
Es tu deber encerrarme...
...but I know who you are...
...pero yo sי quiיn eres...
...and I know what you've done.
...y sי lo que has hecho.
So this is blackmail.
Asם que esto es chantaje.
No, no, no.
No, no, no.
This is redemption.
Asם que esto es redenciףn.
Just giving you an option, that's all.
Solo te doy una opciףn, es todo.
Now, you can arrest me...
Ahora, puedes arrestarme...
...but doing so, your life ends as you know it.
...pero al hacerlo, tu vida terminarב como ya sabes.
Or...
O...
...you could explore...
...podrםas explorar...
...a method of rehabilitation...
...un mיtodo de rehabilitaciףn...
...that'll permit you to sleep at night.
...que te permitirב poder dormir tranquilo.
Or I could kill you right now.
O te podrםa matar ahora mismo.
But you're not a true killer.
Pero no eres un verdadero asesino.
That's your dilemma...
Ese es tu dilema...
...and the information that I have on you is exactly where it needs to be...
...y la informaciףn que tengo de ti estב donde debe estar...
...and it will be released in the event of my disappearance.
...y serב revelada si es que yo desaparezco.
They'll never believe your word over mine.
Nunca le creerבn a tu mundo por encima del mםo.
You willing to take that risk?
¿Estבs dispuesto a tomar ese riesgo?
Risk of ruining your own life...
¿El riesgo de arruinar tu propia vida...
...in order to protect a corrupt legal system...
...para poder proteger un sistema legal corrupto...
...that puts murderers back on the streets?
...que hace que los asesinos regresen a las calles?
How would your sister feel?
¿ Cףmo se sentirםa tu hermana?
You're at a crossroads, detective.
Estבs en una encrucijada, detective.
Make your choice.
Tת eliges.
Did you help Jigsaw get all of them?
¿Ayudaste a Jigsaw a encontrarlos?
Detective Hoffman, this is Special Agent Erickson.
Detective Hoffman, habla el agente especial Erickson.
You had something you needed to discuss about the Jigsaw case?
¿Tenםa algo que decir acerca del caso Jigsaw?
Yes. I stopped by Agent Strahm's room tonight at the hospital...
Sם. Pasי por el cuarto del agente Strahm en el hospital, pero no estaba ahם.
- I hope he's all right. - Oh, yeah, he's fine.
- Espero que estי bien. - Sם, estב bien.
Agent Strahm was theorizing about the possibility...
El agente Strahm teorizaba la posibilidad...
...of an additional accomplice to Jigsaw, other than Amanda Young.
...de un cףmplice adicional de Jigsaw, aparte de Amanda Young.
Someone who might be currently unknown.
Alguien desconocido.
Did he ever mention anything like that to you?
¿ Alguna vez mencionף algo de eso?
- No, but then again, I'm new to the case. - Yeah, well...
No, pero lo repito, soy nuevo en este caso.
Will do. And...
Lo harי. Y...
...in your theorizing...
...en tus teorםas...
...who exactly did you suspect would be an accomplice?
...¿ quiיn sospechabas que era el cףmplice?
Well, he suspected someone on the inside.
Bueno, sospechף de alguien interno.
Someone with access.
Alguien con acceso.
It's an interesting theory.
Es una teorםa interesante.
Detective, what do you say we reconnect in the morning?
Detective, ¿y si nos volvemos a hablar por la maסana?
You got it.
Claro.
Dead.
Muerto.
That guy was an asshole, but he was smart.
Ese tipo era un cretino, pero era inteligente.
We could've used him.
Lo pudimos haber usado.
Yeah, well, someone had to die.
Sם, bueno, alguien tenםa que morir.
Would you rather it'd been you?
¿Hubieras preferido ser tת?
How'd they get you?
¿ Cףmo te atraparon?
Screw you!
¡Jףdete!
I'm gonna kill you! I'm gonna kill you!
¡Te matarי! ¡Te matarי!
I'm gonna kill...
Matarי...
Hello, Paul.
Hola, Paul.
Did you cut yourself because you truly wanted to die...
¿ Te cortaste porque en realidad querםas morir...
... or did you just want some attention?
... o solo querםas llamar la atenciףn?
Tonight, you'll show me.
Esta noche, me lo demostrarבs.
If you want to live, you'll have to cut yourself again.
Si quieres vivir, tendrבs que cortarte otra vez.
How much blood will you shed to stay alive, Paul?
¿ Cuבnta sangre derramarבs para sobrevivir, Paul?
I didn't expect to feel any remorse.
No esperaba sentir ningתn remordimiento.
The heart cannot be involved.
El corazףn no puede estar involucrado.
Emotionally, there can be nothing there.
Emocionalmente, no puede haber nada ahם.
It can never be personal.
Nunca puede ser personal.
- Let's go. - No.
- Vamos. - No.
You're not done yet.
No hemos terminado.
Tonight you will see the difference between killing and rehabilitation.
Esta noche, verבs la diferencia entre matar y la rehabilitaciףn.
There is another detective that you should be aware of.
Hay otro detective que debes tomar en cuenta.
His name's Tapp.
Su nombre es Tapp.
He's smart, and he's getting closer.
Es inteligente, y se estב acercando.
I know who he is.
Sי quiיn es.
I need you to lead him to someone for me.
Necesito que lo lleves a alguien.
A doctor.
Un doctor.
A healer who needs some healing.
Un mיdico que necesita curarse.
Is this yours, doctor?
¿Esto es suyo, doctor?
You supplied these police files, didn't you?
¿Tת diste estos archivos policiacos, no?
You're assuming this is gonna play out the way you want it.
Asumes que esto saldrב como tת quieres.
I assume nothing.
Yo no asumo nada.
I anticipate the possibilities, and I let the game play out.
Anticipo las posibilidades, y dejo que el juego siga.
Then why do you need Amanda in the game?
¿Entonces por quי necesitas a Amanda en el juego?
To ensure that the rules are followed.
Para asegurar que se sigan las reglas.
She won't make decisions for anyone. She'll just...
No tomarב decisiones por nadie. Ella solo...
...offer choices.
...ofrecerב opciones.
Little to your left.
Un poco a tu izquierda.
That leaves a lot to chance.
Eso deja mucha oportunidad.
If you're good at anticipating the human mind...
Si eres bueno anticipando la mente humana...
...it leaves nothing to chance.
...no dejas nada a la casualidad.
It's time.
Es tiempo.
Jesus Christ.
Jesucristo.
Great. More bombs.
Genial. Mבs bombas.
All right. What'd you do to get here?
Bien. ¿ Quי hiciste para estar aquם?
l... I did something, and a bunch of people were killed.
Yo... Yo hice algo, y muchas personas murieron.
I didn't mean to.
No fue mi intenciףn.
They're still dead.
Todavםa estבn muertos.
- That's why you're here? - Yeah.
- ¿Por eso estבs aquם? - Sם.
Shouldn't you have gone to jail for something like that?
¿No debiste haber ido a la cבrcel por algo asם?
Nobody else knows.
Nadie mבs lo sabe.
Somebody does.
Alguien sם lo sabe.
I didn't kill anybody, if that's what you're asking.
Yo no matי a nadie, si es eso lo que preguntas.
I wasn't.
No lo preguntaba.
I grant building permits.
Yo doy permisos para construir.
And yeah, some people might have been more deserving than others...
Y sם, algunas personas se lo merecen mבs que otras...
...but you know what? That's the business.
...¿pero sabes quי? Ese es el negocio.
So if someone tells you different, then they're just stupid.
Y si alguien te dice lo contrario, son unos estתpidos.
Or naןve. Or both.
O ingenuos. O ambos.
Bullshit.
Patraסas.
You take bribes. You're a fucking liar. You cheat people. That's not nice.
Aceptas sobornos. Eres una mentirosa. Engaסas a la gente. Eso no es bueno.
Yeah, well.
Sם, bueno.
I'm sure she's not exactly Mother Teresa either.
Sי que ella no es exactamente la Madre Teresa.
No, I'm not.
No, no lo soy.
I build condos in one of the most densely populated cities in the country.
Construyo apartamentos en una de las ciudades mבs pobladas del paםs.
You don't put up a new building without tearing down a few old ones.
No construimos un edificio nuevo sin tirar algunos viejos.
So we're all bags of shit that deserve to be here. That's good. That's great.
Asם que somos mierdas que merecemos estar aquם. Eso es bueno. Genial.
Fucking great.
Genial.
So is that what you think this is?
¿Asם que crees que esto es por eso?
You don't think there's any other connection?
¿No crees que haya ninguna otra conexiףn?
No, I do.
No, sם lo creo.
I do. And I don't give a shit.
Lo creo. Y no me importa.
Close the fucking door. We have to hear the rules.
Cierra la puerta. Debemos escuchar las reglas.
Hello, and welcome.
Hola, y bienvenidos.
You must all be eager to learn the next important lesson in your transformation.
Deben estar ansiosos de aprender la siguiente lecciףn...
The game before you is designed to bridge the gap between you all.
El juego que tienen estב diseסado para crear un puente de uniףn entre ustedes.
In order to open the five locks on the door out of this room...
Para poder abrir las cinco cerraduras de la puerta de este cuarto...
... the five electrical circuits powering them must be closed.
... los cinco circuitos elיctricos deben ser cerrados.
The only way to do this...
La תnica manera de hacerlo es conectando los cinco cables a la tina.
Close the circuits and the door will open.
Cierren los circuitos y la puerta se abrirב.
But you must work quickly...
Deben trabajar rבpido...
... for in three minutes, an electrical current will surge through this room...
... porque en tres minutos, una corriente elיctrica aumentarב en el cuarto...
... locking the door forever.
... cerrando la puerta para siempre.
Who will bridge the gap? The choice is yours.
¿ Quiיn serב el puente de uniףn? Ustedes eligen.
Jesus Christ.
Jesucristo.
It's not gonna reach. How the fuck are we gonna do this?
No alcanzarב. ¿ Cףmo diablos haremos esto?
Come on!
¡Vamos!
You're gonna get in the tub...
Te meterבs a la tina...
...and we're gonna connect the five cords to you.
...y conectaremos los cinco cables a ti.
But you're gonna kill me too.
Pero me matarבn.
Get in.
- Entra. - Sם, me gustan mבs las duchas.
Fuck you, you bitch. You get in the fucking tub.
Jףdete, perra. Tת mיtete a la tina.
No, don't do it.
No, no lo hagan.
Please, no.
Por favor, no.
You killed her. You fucking killed her.
La mataste.
I didn't trust her.
No confiaba en ella.
Jesus Christ. What is it with you two?
Dios. ¿ Quי les pasa?
Just shut up and help me with the body.
Cבllate y ayתdame con el cadבver.
Hey, hey. No. Don't let your body touch hers.
Oye, oye. No. No dejes que tu cuerpo toque el de ella.
Oh, my God, it's a hook.
Dios, es un gancho.
Stick it in her head or we don't get out.
Mיteselo en la cabeza o no saldremos de aquם.
Just do it.
Tan solo hazlo.
Come in.
Adelante.
Sir. It's Jill Tuck.
Seסor. Es Jill Tuck.
Good evening.
Buenas tardes.
Special Agent Erickson.
Agente especial Erickson.
Thank you for seeing me so late in the day.
Gracias por aceptar verme tan tarde.
Not a problem.
No hay problema.
That'll be all.
Eso es todo.
Please, have a seat.
Por favor, tome asiento.
So, what do you need from us?
¿ Quי necesita de nosotros?
I think I'm being followed.
Creo que me estבn siguiendo.
Well, that sounds more like police work, Miss Tuck.
Eso es mבs un trabajo para la policםa, seסorita Tuck.
I don't think they can help me.
No creo que puedan ayudarme.
- Because? - Because it's you. The FBI.
- ¿Por quי? - Porque son ustedes. El FBI.
I don't understand.
No entiendo.
It started when John was first identified as the Jigsaw killer.
Comenzף cuando John fue identificado como el asesino Jigsaw.
It didn't surprise me then, but I'm still being followed.
No me sorprendiף en ese entonces, pero todavםa me siguen.
By who, Miss Tuck? Who would be following you?
¿ Quiיn, seסorita Tuck? ¿ Quiיn la estarםa siguiendo?
I think it's the agent who interrogated me.
Creo que el agente que me interrogף.
Agent Strahm.
El agente Strahm.
- And why would he be following you? - I don't know.
- ¿ Y por quי la estarםa siguiendo? - No lo sי.
- Who else have you told about this? - Only you.
- ¿A quiיn mבs le ha dicho esto? - Solo a usted.
What's going on with Amanda?
¿ Quי le pasa a Amanda?
Didn't you tell me the only way to truly offer enlightenment...
¿No me dijiste que la תnica manera de ofrecer iluminaciףn...
...is by detaching emotionally?
...es separando las emociones?
But you can have something Amanda doesn't.
Pero puedes tener algo que Amanda no tiene.
Anonymity.
Anonimato.
That's the greatest protection. That's what I've given you.
Es la mejor protecciףn. Eso es lo que yo te he dado.
I need you to set up a game...
Necesito que diseסes un juego...
...that may not be entirely clear to you right now.
...que puede no estar muy claro para ti ahora mismo.
But I assure you that the people being tested...
Pero te aseguro que las personas puestas a prueba...
...are part of something much larger.
...son parte de algo mucho mבs grande.
They're connected.
Tת estבs conectado.
So in the end, all the pieces will fit together...
Asם que al final, todas las piezas encajarבn...
...and it'll be clear.
...y serב todo claro.
- Amanda will fail you. - We'll see.
- Amanda te fallarב. - Ya lo veremos.
What are you doing?
¿ Quי haces?
- What's this? - It's time to play a game.
- ¿ Quי es esto? - Es tiempo de jugar.
Help.
Ayuda.
Help me. What is this?
Ayuda. ¿ Quי es esto?
What is this? Please.
¿ Quי es esto? Por favor.
Why are you keeping me here? What is this place? What is this place?
¿Por quי me mantienes aquם?
We were all supposed to die.
Todos debםamos morir.
He's just fucking testing you.
Esto es solo para ti.
Where is my daughter?
¿Dףnde estב mi hija?
Help!
Ayuda.
He didn't make it.
No sobreviviף.
Nobody made it.
Nadie sobreviviף.
You were supposed to be the hero.
Tת debםas ser el hיroe.
Peter, where the hell are you?
Peter, ¿ dףnde diablos estבs?
Hello?
¿Hola?
You've reached the voice mail for Special Agent Peter Strahm.
Este es el buzףn de mensajes del agente especial Peter Strahm.
Leave a message.
Deje un mensaje.
Cowan. I wanna put a locator on Strahm's mobile phone.
Mallick. Quiero poner un localizador en el telיfono mףvil de Strahm.
Right away, sir.
Ahora mismo, seסor.
Call me right back.
Vuelve a llamarme.
Right.
Bien.
- What the hell is that? - It's our next nightmare.
- ¿ Quי diablos es eso? - Nuestra siguiente pesadilla.
There are blades in here.
Tiene navajas.
It's connected to the door.
Estב conectado a la puerta.
When the beaker fills up, the door opens.
Cuando la taza se llene, se abrirב la puerta.
Fills with what?
¿ Se llene con quי?
Blood. Our blood.
Sangre. Nuestra sangre.
I think an arm is supposed to go in there to fill the beaker.
Creo que un brazo debe ir ahם para llenar la taza.
Wait. Why can't we just use the water from the other room?
Espera. ¿Por quי no podemos usar agua del otro cuarto?
No, the slots are closed.
Las ranuras estבn cerradas.
We have to stick our arm in to keep them open, but they'd get stuck.
Tenemos que meter el brazo para abrirlas, pero se nos atorarםa.
We need to close that door.
Necesitamos cerrar esa puerta.
So, what?
Entonces, ¿ quי?
We fight to the death, and one gets to freedom with the other person's blood?
¿Peleamos contra la muerte, y uno gana la libertad con la sangre del otro?
Hey, wait, wait, wait.
Espera, espera, espera.
Do you still have the keys from that first room?
¿Aתn tienes las llaves del primer cuarto?
- Yeah. - Try one of them on that door.
- Sם. - Prueba una de ellas en esa puerta.
- It won't work. - No, it might. This one has a keyhole.
- No funcionarב. - No, puede ser.
It... It's not even the same lock.
No es la misma cerradura.
Wait, why are there five slots in this machine?
¿Por quי hay cinco ranuras en esta mבquina?
Shouldn't there only be one?
¿No deberםa haber solo una?
They all would have worked.
Cualquiera pudo haber funcionado.
There you are, Strahm.
Ahם estבs, Strahm.
All right. I got him.
Bien. Lo tengo.
I don't think this is a good idea.
No creo que esta sea una buena idea.
The tub wasn't meant for one person.
La tina no era para una sola persona.
We were supposed to hold one cable each...
Debimos tomar un cable cada uno...
...and suffer a small shock.
...y sufrir un pequeסo choque.
It was meant for five people.
Era para cinco personas.
They all were. Every game.
Todos lo eran. Cada juego.
We only needed one key in the first room.
Solo necesitבbamos una llave en el primer cuarto.
They all worked, and any one of them would have opened every collar.
Todas funcionaban, y cualquiera abrםa el collar.
In the second room, the three tubes were large enough for more than one person.
En el segundo cuarto, en las cבmaras cabםa mבs de una persona.
We were supposed to work together so we all survived.
Debםamos trabajar juntos para sobrevivir todos juntos.
That's the game.
Ese es el juego.
Your instincts will tell you to do one thing...
Sus instintos les dirבn que hagan una cosa...
...but I implore you to do the opposite.
...pero les imploro que hagan lo opuesto.
Oh, God.
Dios.
Yeah. Big fucking whoops.
Sם. Vaya.
Hello, and welcome.
Hola, y bienvenidos.
This journey has been one of discovery...
Este viaje ha sido de descubrimientos...
... and hopefully you've discovered that the whole...
... y con suerte descubrieron que el todo es mבs que la suma de sus partes.
The human body, for instance, is an astoundingly durable creation.
El cuerpo humano, por ejemplo, es una impresionante creaciףn durable.
It contains approximately 10 pints of blood...
Contiene aproximadamente 4,8 litros de sangre...
... yet it is still able to operate with just half of that.
... y sin embargo es capaz de operar con solo la mitad de eso.
The device before you is one of sacrifice.
El dispositivo que tienen enfrente es uno de sacrificio.
A sacrifice of blood.
Un sacrificio de sangre.
In order to open the door, the beaker must be filled to the marked level...
Para poder abrir la puerta, la taza se debe llenar al nivel marcado...
... a level that is of no coincidence.
... un nivel que no es ninguna coincidencia.
This amount can come from any one of you.
Esa cantidad puede venir de cualquiera de los dos.
That does not matter. What does matter is time.
Eso no importa. Lo que importa es el tiempo.
For in 15 minutes, if the beaker is not filled...
Porque si en 15 minutos no se llena la taza...
... the bombs will explode and the doors will be sealed forever.
... las bombas explotarבn y las puertas serבn selladas para siempre.
So now I ask you, how much blood will you give in order to survive?
Ahora les preguntarי, ¿ cuבnta sangre darבn para poder sobrevivir?
Fuck! Fuck.
¡Carajo! Carajo.
All right, so one person can fill the beaker with ten pints of blood and die.
Bien, entonces una persona puede llenar...
Or two people can fill it...
O dos personas pueden llenarla...
...with five pints...
...con 2,4 litros...
...and maybe live.
...y sobrevivir.
What are we gonna do?
¿ Quי haremos?
I lied.
Yo mentם.
I know the investigative journalist in there. His name is Charles.
Conozco al periodista investigador de ahם. Su nombre es Charles.
He was writing a story about what I did.
Estaba escribiendo una historia de lo que hice.
What'd you do?
¿ Quי hiciste?
A dealer gave me...
Un traficante me dio...
...an ounce of heroin to burn down an abandoned building.
...una onza de heroםna por quemar un edificio abandonado.
But it wa...
Pero no...
Oh, God. It wasn't abandoned. There was eight people in there.
Dios. No estaba abandonado. Ocho personas vivםan ahם.
Eight people died.
Ocho personas murieron.
And the feds got involved.
Y se involucraron los federales.
And I got caught but I made a deal and my dad got me off.
Me atraparon pero hice un escבndalo y mi padre hizo que me soltaran.
The guy who hired me disappeared and nothing happened. Nothing happened.
El hombre que me contratף desapareciף y no pasף nada. No pasף nada.
That's how she knew me.
Por eso me conocםa.
The woman in the tub.
La mujer en la tina.
The fire. It's what connects us.
El fuego.
The fire inspector who wrote the bogus accident report...
La inspectora que escribiף el reporte del accidente...
...the city planner who pushed through the residential permits...
...la planeadora que dio los permisos residenciales...
...the journalist that buried the investigative story...
...los periodistas que enterraron la historia de la investigaciףn...
...the rich-kid junkie who was the patsy...
...el niסo rico drogadicto que fue el tonto...
...and the real estate developer who set it all in motion.
...y la de la inmobiliaria que orquestף todo.
We killed eight people and stole the property, and nobody cared.
Matamos a ocho personas, robamos una propiedad y a nadie le importף.
Nobody cared?
¿A nadie le importף?
Eight people and their families cared.
Les importף a ocho personas y a sus familiares.
The feds cared. Look at my fucking arm. I cared! I cared!
Le importף a los federales. Mira mi brazo.
But you didn't face justice.
Pero no enfrentaste a la justicia.
None of us did.
Ninguno lo hizo.
Why did they all do it?
¿Por quי lo hicieron?
Why? Was it for money?
¿Por quי? ¿Por dinero?
This was your plan? You were the one behind it?
¿Este fue tu plan? ¿Tת estבs detrבs de esto?
There was eight people in that building.
Habםa ocho personas en ese edificio. Debםas saberlo. ¿Lo sabםas?
You're a monster.
Eres un monstruo.
So are you.
Igual que tת.
We both deserve to be here.
Los dos merecemos estar aquם.
I can't do this alone. Look at me. I can't do this alone.
No puedo hacer esto solo. Mםrame. No puedo hacerlo solo.
Okay. It's okay.
Bien. Estב bien.
We have to go on three.
A la cuenta de tres.
One.
Uno.
Two.
Dos.
Put your hand in the hole!
¡Pon tu mano en el hoyo!
Three!
¡Tres!
Hello, Agent Strahm.
Hola, agente Strahm.
If you are hearing this...
Si estב escuchando esto, nuevamente encontrף lo que estaba buscando.
Or so you think.
O eso es lo que piensa.
Your dedication is to be commended.
Su dedicaciףn es digna de elogiarse.
But I ask you if you have learned anything on your journey of discovery.
Pero le pregunto si ha aprendido algo en su viaje de descubrimientos.
As the old adage goes:
Como dice un viejo pasaje:
"Fool me once, shame on you. Fool me twice, shame on me. "
"Si te engaסan una vez, culpa al otro.
The situation you find yourself in is one of trust.
La situaciףn en la que se encuentra es de confianza.
So I ask you, Special Agent Strahm, have you learned to trust me?
Asם que le pregunto, agente Strahm, ¿ ha aprendido a confiar en mם?
The only way to survive this room is by entering the glass box before you.
La תnica manera de sobrevivir es entrando a la caja de cristal.
Pain will be incurred, but you have a chance of survival.
Habrב dolor, pero tiene la oportunidad de sobrevivir.
We did it.
Lo hicimos.
We won.
Ganamos.
I got you, you motherfucker.
Te tengo, desgraciado.
Drop it!
¡Suיltala!
I said drop it!
¡Dije, suיltala!
Who did this to you?
¿ Quiיn te hizo esto?
We won.
Ganamos.
We worked together.
Trabajamos juntos.
I need immediate medical assistance. 1293 Sandburst Drive.
Necesito asistencia mיdica urgente en 1293 Sandburst Drive.
Jesus, Peter.
Jesתs, Peter.
Tell me how to open it.
Dime cףmo abrirla.
How do I open it?
¿ Cףmo la abro?
However, if you choose not to, you will never be heard from again.
Sin embargo, si eliges no hacerlo, nunca se volverב a escuchar de ti.
Your body will never be found.
Nunca se encontrarב tu cuerpo.
You will simply vanish.
Simplemente desaparecerבs.
I ask you, Special Agent Strahm, have you learned enough to trust me?
Le pregunto, agente especial Strahm, ¿ ha aprendido a confiar en mם?
Will you heed my warning?
¿ Considerarב mi advertencia?
- For if you do not... - Fuck you.
- Porque si no... - Vete al carajo.
... this room will forever be your tomb.
... este cuarto serב su tumba eterna.
And my legacy will become yours.
Y mi legado serב suyo.
If you're good at anticipating the human mind...
Si eres bueno anticipando la mente humana...
- I think I'm being followed. - Who would be following you?
- Creo que me estבn siguiendo. - ¿ Quiיn la estarםa siguiendo?
I wanna talk to Jill Tuck one last time.
Quiero hablar con Jill Tuck una vez mבs.
He suspected someone on the inside.
Sospechף de alguien interno.
- it leaves nothing to chance.
...no dejas nada a la casualidad.
We were all supposed to die.
Todos debםamos morir.
You were supposed to be the hero.
Tת debםas ser el hיroe.
Make your choice.
Usted elige.
Cowan.
Cowan.
Yeah, this is Erickson.
Sם, habla Erickson.
I want you to put out an APB.
Quiero que publiques un boletםn.
Suspect's name is Peter Strahm.
El nombre del sospechoso es Peter Strahm.
Yeah, that's right.
Sם, asם es.
Special Agent Peter Strahm.
Agente especial Peter Strahm.
I'm gonna stop you, you son of a bitch.
Te voy a detener, hijo de perra.
I know who you are. I know.
Sי quiיn eres. Lo sי.
Subtitles by LeapinLar
Subtitles by LeapinLar
Support us and become VIP member to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Por favor califica este subtitulo en www.osdb.link/y27f Ayuda a otros a elegir el mejor